Luoyang
洛阳
The city has strong walls and high walls
城墙坚固，城墙高耸
Easy to defend but difficult to attack
守易攻难
And there's that Fu Yuan'er
还有那个傅媛儿
Although he is a general
虽然他是将军
But he is Sun Jing’s old subordinate
但他是孙靖的老部下
Always loyal to Sun Jing
永远忠于孙靖
So Shichiro
曾七郎
Siege is the next best strategy
围攻是下一个最佳策略
And our neighbors
还有我们的邻居
And Cui Jiajun is watching with eager eyes.
而崔家俊则用热切的目光注视着。
What if our siege fails?
如果我们的攻城失败怎么办？
Will be attacked from both sides
会受到两面夹击
Luoyang City is not
洛阳市不是
No flaws
没有瑕疵
Sun Jing’s brother-in-law Zheng Guogong
Sun Jing’s brother-in-law Zheng Guogong
Aren't you supervising the battle in Luoyang City?
你不是在洛阳城督战吗？
This person has great ambition but little talent
此人志向远大，才华却很少
And he has always been at odds with Fu Yuan'er
而且他和傅媛儿一直不和
I read
我读
He is Luoyang City
He is Luoyang City
The biggest flaw
最大的缺陷
Jushichiro
十七郎
A secret envoy was sent to Luoyang City
派遣特使到洛阳城
want to see you
想见你
please
请
Mr. Fu came here alone
傅先生一个人来到这里
So brave indeed
确实如此勇敢
The emperor's grandson has received the award
皇帝的孙子获奖了
Fu Mou has no other
付某没有别的
Only be brave
唯有勇敢
You must be Pei Xian’s youngest son, right?
你一定是裴贤最小的儿子吧？
Thinking about your father and I back then
想着那时的你父亲和我
Lead the troops together
一起带领部队
When conquering Yiluo
When conquering Yiluo
Are you still breastfeeding?
你还在哺乳吗？
Fu Gong more than ten years ago
十多年前的福工
During the expedition against Yiluo
征伐伊洛时
Break into the king's tent single-handedly
单枪匹马闯入国王的帐篷
Take the head of King Yiluo directly
直接拿伊洛王的头颅
Li Yi was young at that time
那时李毅还年轻
Just listen to it as a story
就当作故事来听吧
Now I can see real people
现在我可以看到真实的人了
Only then did we know that Mr. Fu was brave
这时我们才知道傅先生是勇敢的
Just like a story
就像一个故事一样
old
老的
Not to mention the courage back then
更别提当年的勇气了
The Seventeenth Lang is the young hero
十七郎是少年英雄
in front of seniors
在长辈面前
How dare you talk about Yingjie?
你怎么敢说英杰？
please
请
Zhenxi Army and Cui Jiajun
Zhenxi Army and Cui Jiajun
Things in Bingzhou
并州事
I've heard about it all
我都听说过
This Han Li
这个韩立
Since it was obtained by the emperor’s grandson
既然是皇帝的孙子得到的
Then why not build Jianzhou City
那为什么不建建州城呢
Also filed into the bag together
也一起归档进包里
Instead, let the Cui family
反而让崔家
Got a big advantage
取得了很大的优势
Our Zhenxi Army
我们的镇西军
Unlike Cui Jiajun
Unlike Cui Jiajun
So rich
这么有钱
So we can only take Jianzhou
所以只能拿下建州
in exchange for food and grass
以换取食物和草
I'm helpless too
我也很无奈
The emperor's grandson doesn't want to vent his anger
皇孙不愿出气
Bring the Cui family's food and supplies
带上崔家的食物和物资
Take it away
把它拿开
Mr. Fu is afraid he has forgotten
傅先生恐怕忘记了
Why did I come to Luoyang City with troops?
我为何带着部队来到洛阳城？
The emperor's grandson wants Luoyang
皇孙要洛阳
Fu knew it well
傅深知此事
only
仅有的
At present, the Zhenxi Army is short of food and grass.
目前，镇西军粮草短缺。
With no men and horses, they stormed Luoyang.
兵不血刃，猛攻洛阳。
But it is
但它是
Making wedding clothes for Cui Jiajun in vain
徒劳地为崔家俊做嫁衣
The emperor and grandson haven't had enough of this.
皇帝和孙子还没有受够。
Everyone in this world is Tao Fu Gong
这世上的人都是陶福公
Brave and unrivaled
勇敢无敌
did not expect
没想到
This divorce plan is useful
这个离婚计划很有用
So clever too
也太聪明了
Although it is a estrangement
虽然是一种隔阂
It's also true
这也是事实
The emperor's grandson is not taking action at this moment
皇孙此刻并没有采取行动
Should he just let Cui Yi become more powerful?
难道就让崔易变得更强大吗？
reap the benefits of being a fisherman along the way
沿途收获渔民的好处
Eventually become a thorn in his side
最终成为他的眼中钉
Could it be that Cui Yi is better than the Governor?
难道崔义比总督还厉害？
It's better to get along with him
和他相处比较好
Mr. Fu, if you have something to say, you might as well say it directly.
傅先生，你有什么话就直接说吧。
Now the two armies are on the border
现在两军已经到了边境
Fu was deeply favored by the Governor
傅深得总督青睐
With the emperor's current military strength,
以皇帝现在的军事实力，
To conquer Luoyang City
To conquer Luoyang City
no easy task
这不是一件容易的事
Not within three days
三天之内不行
Defeat his Cui family army
击败他的崔家军队
Once it's done
一旦完成
Fu immediately offered it
傅立马主动提出
Half of the food and grass in the city
城里一半粮草
The Zhenxi Army only needs to circle the city and pass by.
镇西军只需要绕城一圈就过去了。
Fu will never stop him
傅永远不会阻止他
The emperor's grandson may wish to consider
皇孙不妨考虑一下
It won’t be too late to give me an answer tomorrow
明天给我答复还不算太晚
good
好的
I'll take my leave first.
我先告辞了。
I've ordered people to prepare it
我已经吩咐人去准备了
Thirty carts of grain and grass
粮草三十车
Can be delivered tonight
今晚可以发货
As a gift for me during this trip
作为这次旅行送给我的礼物
Mr. Fu is not afraid
傅先生不怕
After I collected the food and grass
当我收集了食物和草之后
Turn around and attack Luoyang
转身攻打洛阳
Thirty carts of grain and grass
粮草三十车
I can still afford it
我还是买得起的
Farewell
告别
Han Li, this idiot
韩立这个白痴
Didn't expect it to be so fast
没想到这么快
Just throw it away and build two states
扔掉它并建立两个国家
I thought he had been in business for many years
我以为他已经做生意很多年了
At least the energy consumption is enough to suppress the Western Army
至少能量消耗足以压制西军
Great loss of vitality
元气大减
I didn't expect him to find it useful.
我没想到他会觉得有用。
Zhenxi Army and Cui Jiajun join forces
Zhenxi Army and Cui Jiajun join forces
Han Li is invincible
韩立无敌
now
现在
The Zhenxi Army must point its sword at the Luoshui River
镇西军必须剑指洛水
Let’s fight against Baiyue’s army
来对抗百越大军吧
Is it temporary
是暂时的吗
Withdraw some first
先取出一些
Southern Expedition to Baiyue
南征百越
It is a major event of opening up a new territory
是开辟新疆域的一件大事
Li's Yu Dynasty for a hundred years
李氏大禹王朝一百年
After several expeditions over hundreds of countries, they were all defeated and returned.
数次征战数百国，皆败而归。
If I could pacify Baiyue
如果我能安抚白月
Then the world will be convinced
那么世界就会相信
yes
是的
But now the war situation is critical
但现在战局危急
Recruitment
招聘
Then recruit more troops from all walks of life.
然后再招募各路部队。
Although Li Yi was able
虽然李毅能够
But his troops are limited
但他的兵力有限
It's Wai
这是水
I want him too
我也想要他
Trapped to death by the bank of Luoyang
被困洛阳岸而死
Or wine from the Western Regions?
还是西域的酒？
Jushichiro
十七郎
You said this Fu Yuan'er
你说的是这个傅媛儿
That's really cunning.
这实在是太狡猾了。
This is a divorce tactic
这是离婚策略
Use it openly and honestly
公开、诚实地使用它
We don’t even have room to refute
我们连反驳的余地都没有
nothing
没有什么
This Fu Yuan'er
This Fu Yuan'er
Such generals
这样的将军
Courageous and resourceful
勇敢机智
But he is only loyal to Sun Jing
但他只忠于孙靖
it's a pity
真遗憾
Jushichiro
十七郎
You say what he just said
你说他刚才说的话
How much is true and how much is false?
有多少是真的，有多少是假的？
Tomorrow morning
明天早上
Reply to Fu Yuan'er
回复 傅媛儿 的帖子
Just say I agreed
就说我同意了
What
什么
You promised him to fight Cui Jiajun
你答应过他要和崔家俊打的
Take my place again
再次取代我的位置
Also reply to Cui Jiajun
也回复崔家俊
What are you going to do again?
你又要做什么？
Don't take advantage of this
不要利用这个
Before the big fight
大战之前
Take advantage
充分利用
Even the capital and profits are taken back
连资本和利润都被收回
Lord, you can't go there
主啊，你不能去那里
I am Zheng Guogong
I am Zheng Guogong
Mr. Fu is sick
傅先生生病了
You all get out of here
你们都离开这里
dog slave
狗奴
Duke
公爵
I want to see Fu Yuan'er
我想见傅媛儿
Hello Fu Yuan'er
Hello Fu Yuan'er
Defiant, rebellious and arrogant
挑衅、叛逆、傲慢
It’s been half a month since I returned to Luoyang
回到洛阳已经半个月了
You've been pretending to be sick and not seeing me
你一直假装生病不来看我
what do you mean you
你是什​​么意思
I've got the tip
我有秘诀
Talk about a few days ago
说起前几天的事
you alone
你独自一人
Go to Zhenxi Army Camp
前往镇西军营
I had a private meeting with Li Ni
我和李妮进行了一次私人会面
explain
解释
Are you carrying the Governor on your back?
你背着总督吗？
What's the deal with Li Yi?
和李毅什么关系？
That's right
这是正确的
three days ago
三天前
I did go to the Zhenxi Army Camp
我确实去过镇西军营
I also met Li Yi
我也认识了李毅
good
好的
Since you confessed everything
既然你承认了一切
Then quickly hand over your handsome seal.
然后赶紧交出你的帅印。
General Fu
傅将军
You hold it in your hand
你把它握在手里
Luoyang military and political power
洛阳军政实力
Wan Yi and Li Yi
Wan Yi and Li Yi
Is there anything that should be combined inside and outside?
有什么应该内外结合的吗？
Wouldn't it be detrimental to the Governor?
这不是对州长不利吗？
Marshal Yin was personally taught by the Grand Governor.
尹元帅是大都督亲自教导的。
Unless the governor comes in person
除非州长亲自来
Otherwise I wouldn't
不然我不会
Hand over the handsome seal
交出帅印
Clever words to seduce you
巧妙的言语来诱惑你
I see Li Yi
我看到李毅了
I want to force him to fight Cui Jiajun
我要逼他打崔家俊
The two armies appeared and marched to Luoshui River
两军现身，向洛水河进军
If we join forces
如果我们联手
This Luoyang City is very dangerous.
这洛阳城很危险。
best way
最好的办法
Just let Li Yi
就让李毅
To defeat the Cui family army
击败崔家军
Na Zhaofu, old general
Na Zhaofu, old general
If you say so
如果你这么说
You really have a way
你真有办法
Let Li Yi defeat the Cui family army but fail
让李毅击败崔家军却失败
What a coincidence
多么巧合
Li Ning just sent someone to deliver a letter.
李宁刚刚派人送来了一封信。
It’s not time to say today
今天还不是说的时候
Will attack Cui Jiajun
Will attack Cui Jiajun
Is Mr. Zheng willing to follow me?
郑先生愿意跟我走吗？
Go to the tower together
一起去塔楼
Go and see the excitement
去看看热闹
Mr. Fu takes a lesson from you and makes a promise to you.
傅先生向你吸取了教训，并向你做出了承诺。
The Cui family's army will attack at the end of the day.
崔家大军终究会进攻。
You'd better skim the formation from behind.
你最好从后面掠过阵型。
How can any coach be a pioneer?
教练如何能成为先锋？
If I don't show up in person
如果我不亲自出现
How could Fu Yuan'er believe it?
傅媛儿怎么可能相信？
Moreover
而且
We have to let Cui Jiajun
我们得让崔家俊
Look at the strength of our Zhenxi Army
看看我们镇西军的实力
newspaper
报纸
The Zhenxi Army has all come out
镇西军全部出动
Kill Cui Jiajun
Kill Cui Jiajun
What are you two fighting here?
你们两个在这里吵什么？
Didn't Seventeen Lang say that he was fake?
十七郎不是说他是假的吗？
It makes a difference who you hit
你击中的人会有所不同
Are you talking nonsense and hitting your own people?
你这是在胡说八道，还打自己人吗？
Where to fight Cui Jiajun?
哪里跟崔家俊斗？
Beat them
打败他们
Go
去
hit them
打他们
Walk
走
you
你
Where are you stepping?
你在哪里迈步？
How dare you step on your grandfather's hand?
你怎么敢踩你爷爷的手？
Aren't you dead?
你没死吗？
Where's the fake corpse?
假尸在哪里？
It turns out that you suppressed the Western Army
原来你镇压了西军
It's all this kind of bullying and fear of the strong
这都是对强者的欺凌和恐惧
You're a rat who only knows how to fake corpses.
你是一只只知道如何伪造尸体的老鼠。
Brat
小子
Let’s see how grandpa treats you today
今天看看爷爷是怎么对你的
It turns out to be you
原来是你
I saved you again
我又救了你
good
好的
Then I'll pay you back once
那我就还你一次
Why are these people trying to kill you?
这些人为什么要杀你？
Although these people are all strangers
虽然这些人都是陌生人
And try their best to cover up
并尽力去掩盖
But I have some guesses in my mind
但我心里有一些猜测
Jushichiro
十七郎
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
injured
受伤
Cui
哪个
Didn't you agree to fake a beating?
你不是答应假装打人吗？
what happened
发生了什么
I see the fighting ends here
我看到战斗到此结束
about there
关于那里
Walk
走
newspaper
报纸
how
如何
Scouts come to report
侦察兵前来报道
The Zhenxi Army has defeated the Cui Army
镇西军大败崔军
Mr. Cui is injured
崔先生受伤
Cui Jiajun retreated thirty miles
崔家军后退三十里
rearrange
改编
Although the Zhenxi Army won
虽然镇西军获胜
But the damage was serious
但伤害却很严重
Marshal Li Ni was shot in the leg
李妮元帅腿部中弹
Has been carried back to the army
已被带回部队
good
好的
General Fu
傅将军
Everyone says this Li Yi is cunning
人人都说这个李毅狡猾
Cui Jiajun is brave
Cui Jiajun is brave
I can't see it like this
我看不到这样的
Not as good as
不如
Let me lead the troops to defeat each one
让我率领军队，逐一击溃
So that I can report the good news to the Governor
这样我就可以向总督汇报这个好消息
Wait a minute
等一下
I promised Li Yi
我答应过李毅
As long as he defeats Cui Jiajun
As long as he defeats Cui Jiajun
Then he gave him half the city's food and grass.
然后就把全城一半的粮草给了他。
Allow him to go around Luoyang
让他绕洛阳转一圈
What
什么
You give him food and grass
你给他食物和草
You also let him go around the city
你还让他去城里转转
Are you going to rebel?
你要造反吗？
What do you know
你知道什么
Luoyang is the capital of Deng
洛阳是邓氏的都城
The terrain and people's hearts are extraordinary
地利人和人心不凡
At present, in Luoyang City
目前，在洛阳市
Although the army has sufficient food and fodder,
虽然军队粮草充足，
But if it is Cui Jiajun
但如果是崔家骏
Join forces with the Zhenxi Army to attack the city
与镇西军会师攻城
Or besiege Luoyang
Or besiege Luoyang
Cut off food routes
切断食物路线
Isn’t it like setting up Kyoto?
这不就像建立京都一样吗？
Putting the governor in danger
将州长置于危险之中
I see you are afraid of fighting
我看你害怕打架
eloquent words
雄辩的话
I risked using tricks to drive a wedge between the Cui family
我冒着诡计离间崔家
and the two armies of Zhenxi
以及镇西两军
Now they both lose
现在他们都输了
I'm just afraid that there might be a scam here.
我只是担心这里可能有骗局。
They must be lured away from Luoyang first
必须先把他们引离洛阳
and then plan
然后计划
How to divide them and kill them all
如何分割并全部杀死
It hurts
好痛
no pain
不痛
Just got there
刚到那里
Aying
阿英
Why are you injured?
你为什么受伤？
Young Master
少爷
fine
美好的
I'm not hurt
我没有受伤
As long as it's not hurt
只要不受伤
Young Master
少爷
People from Cui Jiajun
People from Cui Jiajun
someone wants to kill me
有人想杀我
wrong
错误的
I was wearing a mask just now
我刚才戴着口罩
They thought I was you
他们以为我就是你
Someone wants to kill you
有人想杀你
What do you think
你怎么认为
Who did it?
谁干的？
People from the Cui family army
崔家军的人
Can it always be like this
能不能一直这样
Sparing no effort to target you and me
不遗余力地瞄准你我
Who else could it be?
还能是谁呢？
It seems that this Cui Li has been holding back for many years.
看来这个崔立已经憋了很多年了。
I couldn't bear it anymore after all.
我终于无法忍受了。
Prince, don't worry
王子，别担心
I will find a way
我会找到办法
Let him not make waves
让他别掀起波澜
Jushichiro
十七郎
Call me today
今天打电话给我
No more drinking
不再喝酒了
Drinking tea instead
喝茶代替
Drink a few cups of tea instead of wine
喝几杯茶代替酒
Such good tea
这么好的茶
Have a few more drinks
多喝几杯
That's not right
那是不对的
Why are you so happy today
今天怎么这么高兴
happy event
喜
You've got to the point
你已经说到重点了
Where is my friend?
我的朋友在哪里？
It turns out the girl he likes
原来他喜欢的女孩
Not someone’s concubine
不是别人的妾
Seventeen Lang you
十七郎游
Your friend
你的朋友
I haven’t let this matter go yet.
这件事我还没有放下。
A man can afford to take it and put it down
男人拿得起放得下
I thought they had cut it off a long time ago
我以为他们很久以前就已经把它砍掉了
You do not understand
你不明白
OK, I don’t understand
好吧，我不明白
But anyone with a discerning eye can see it
但明眼人都能看出来
That Colonel He and Mr. Cui
那个何上校和崔先生
Close contacts
密切接触者
Even if she's not his concubine
哪怕她不是他的妾
These two people must have an affair
这两个人肯定有私情
Jushichiro
十七郎
We and Cui Jiajun
We and Cui Jiajun
Although they are both teachers of King Qin
虽然他们都是秦王的老师
But this Cui family
但这崔家
There must be some dissent
一定会有一些异议
It will become a problem for the country and the dynasty in the future.
这将成为未来国家和王朝的难题。
when did you know
你什么时候知道的
Anyone with long eyes can see it
长眼睛的人都看得出来
Do you like that Captain He?
你喜欢那个何队长吗？
Yes or no
是还是不是
Is it so obvious?
有这么明显吗？
I'll be more restrained next time
下次我会更加克制
Why are you going?
你为什么走？
school lieutenant
学校中尉
time to eat
吃的时候
peach
桃
Help me get the most poisonous poison
帮我找到最毒的毒药
The kind that will kill you if you touch your lips
碰一下嘴唇就会杀了你的那种
you
你
What do you want poison for?
你要毒做什么？
Just go get it
去拿吧
Okay, I'll go right away
好的，我马上就去
poison
毒
The most poisonous poison
最毒的毒药
how
如何
Lieutenant He knew I was coming
中尉 他知道我要来
You want to kill me and silence me?
你想杀了我并让我闭嘴吗？
The emperor's grandson was injured
皇孙受伤
Not recuperating in camp
未在营地康复
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
before
前
It's all you who took care of your son
都是你在照顾你的儿子
Going into battle to kill the enemy, right?
上战场去杀敌吧？
Of course not
当然不是
My son is feeling unwell today
我儿子今天感觉不舒服
I just fought for him
我只是为了他而战
I already know it all
我已经知道这一切了
what do you know
你知道什么
I know your identity
我知道你的身份
Know who I am
知道我是谁
I know your identity is actually
我知道你的身份实际上是
I know you actually don’t
我知道你其实不知道
She's not Mr. Cui's concubine
她不是崔先生的小妾
I'm not
我不是
so what
所以呢
You're a liar
你是个骗子
little liar
小骗子
Let me discuss something with you
让我和你讨论一些事情
If I catch Zheng Guogong
If I catch Zheng Guogong
How about leaving Luoyang to me?
把洛阳留给我怎么样？
That won't work
那不行
Even if you can catch Zheng Guogong
Even if you can catch Zheng Guogong
Unless you suppress the Western Army
除非镇压西军
We don’t need help from Cui Jiajun
我们不需要崔家军的帮助
We can capture Luoyang
我们可以攻克洛阳
Otherwise Luoyang cannot be yours
不然洛阳就不可能是你的了
The captain brought the poison
船长带来了毒药
we are going
我们要去了
Poisoning the Zhenxi Army
毒害镇西军
Poisonous?
有毒？
I'll talk to you about this later
我稍后再和你谈这个
school lieutenant
学校中尉
Why is this Emperor Li here?
这个厉帝怎么会在这里？
What did he tell you?
他告诉你什么了？
Why don't we talk about it later?
我们为什么不稍后再谈呢？
What happened to you before
你之前发生了什么
Don't hide it from me
别对我隐瞒
You won’t even tell me now
你现在甚至不会告诉我
Is this poison still useful?
这毒还有用吗？
Cui Jiajun was defeated
崔家军被击败
Back thirty miles
后退三十英里
Yesterday's battle
昨天的战斗
Live up to Mr. Fu’s expectations
不辜负傅先生的期望
It was a beautiful battle
这是一场美丽的战斗
He is indeed your grandpa’s good son.
他确实是你爷爷的好儿子。
Mr. Fu is overly praised
傅先生过誉了
Yesterday's battle
昨天的战斗
The emperor's grandson was injured
皇孙受伤
Can't come today
今天不能来
Tell me specifically
具体告诉我
Thank you Mr. Fu for the food and grass.
谢谢傅先生的粮草。
Fu keeps his word
傅信守诺言
The food and grass promised to him
答应给他的粮草
I will definitely give it to him
我一定会给他
Then thank Mr. Fu.
那谢谢付先生了。
Tell Li Ni
告诉李妮
Let him take care of himself
让他照顾好自己
yes
是的
Jushichiro
十七郎
This is not Fu Yuan'er
这不是傅媛儿
Did you promise to give us food?
你答应给我们食物吗？
Why are we still lying in wait here?
为什么我们还在这里等待？
I will give it to you later
我稍后给你
Do a trick and see
做一个技巧看看
what trick
什么伎俩
Just from this food
就凭这食物
Change it for you
给你改一下
Duke Zheng comes out
郑公出来了
rush
匆忙
come out
出来
come out faster
快点出来
do not move
不要动
General Pei
裴将军
How long will this last?
这会持续多久？
Enough to eat for a while
够吃一段时间了
I also caught a big fish.
我还钓到了一条大鱼。
This time, Luoyang City
这次，洛阳市
Safe
安全的
This is Sun Jing’s brother-in-law
这是孙静的妹夫
Zheng Guogong, right?
Zheng Guogong, right?
He doesn’t look very good either.
他看起来也不太好。
That's right
这是正确的
What does Sun Jing’s wife look like?
孙静的老婆长啥样？
It definitely doesn’t look good either.
肯定也不好看。
I haven't seen the Duke yet
我还没见过公爵呢
Such a high official
这么高的官
This armor is good
这铠甲不错
Not bad
不错
Such a high-ranking official can only be killed with a knife
这么高的官员，也只能用刀杀掉
He cried so much
他哭得很厉害
A dear descendant of Luoyang City
亲爱的洛阳后裔
Hiding in this grain truck
躲在这辆运粮车里
Want to sneak attack on us
想偷袭我们
We are still the Seventeenth Lang
我们还是十七郎
Magical plan
神奇的计划
Caught them red-handed
当场抓住他们
Now that Zheng Guogong has been captured,
现在郑国公被俘了，
Then this Luoyang City
那么这个洛阳市
It's like it's in our hands
就好像它在我们手中一样
yes
是的
Very good
非常好
let me go
让我走
general
一般的
Li Ni, Zhenxi Army
Li Ni, Zhenxi Army
Cui Jiajun and Cui Lin encircled
Cui Jiajun and Cui Lin encircled
Take Zheng Guogong with you
Take Zheng Guogong with you
and his entourage are dear to him
他的随行人员对他来说很亲爱
Come to the city
来到城市
He said he was willing to use Zheng Guogong
他说愿意用郑国公
and the captured relatives in the city
以及城里被俘的亲人
exchange for city
换取城市
don't kill me help me
别杀我帮我
What to change?
要改变什么？
Why is Zheng Guogong crooked?
郑国公为何歪了？
None can compare to Luoyang City
无人能与洛阳城相比
Such rogue things
这么流氓的东西
Only you can control the Western Army
只有你才能控制西方军队
Can do it
可以做到
Don't look at the scoundrels
别看无赖们
But it works
但它有效
Do you dare to make a bet with me?
你敢跟我打赌吗？
I won't bet with you
我不会和你打赌
Hu'er with the surname Fu
胡儿姓傅
Listen to me
听我说
Our grandson
我们的孙子
Marshal Li said
李元帅说
give you a chance
给你一个机会
as long as you open
只要你打开
The gate of Luoyang City
洛阳城门
We let Zheng Guogong go
We let Zheng Guogong go
and these dear children
和这些亲爱的孩子们
We promise
我们承诺
Don’t take the city’s wealth
不要夺走城市的财富
Do not harm the people in the city
不要伤害城里的人
how is everything
一切还好吧
Is this a good deal?
这划算吗？
Duke Guo of Zheng is Sun Jing’s brother-in-law
郑国公是孙敬的妹夫
If you don't save him
如果你不救他
Sun Jing, that great governor
孙敬那个伟大的刺史
I won't let you go
我不会让你走
put
放
Shoot an arrow
射箭
Shot Zheng Guogong to death
Shot Zheng Guogong to death
Look at Sun Jing
看看孙静
I won’t chop off your heads
我不会砍掉你的头
Fu Yuan'er
Fu Yuan'er
you are crazy
你疯了
Farewell Fu Yuan'er
Farewell Fu Yuan'er
Let it go
放手吧
don't don't don't don't
不要不要不要不要
Fu Yuan'er
Fu Yuan'er
Don't, don't, don't
别别别别
Fu Yuan'er, you bastard
Fu Yuan'er, you bastard
Fu Yuan'er
Fu Yuan'er
You will avenge your private vengeance
你会报你的私仇
Thousands of people in the city
城里有几千人
But everyone is watching
但大家都在看
The Governor won't let you go
州长不会放你走的
Archery skills are good
射箭技术不错
If it were a little more biased
如果稍微偏一点点
Shot Zheng Guogong in the heart
Shot Zheng Guogong in the heart
That won't be useful
那不会有用的
I have sent people to attack Yingzhou
我已经派人攻打瀛州了
We can no longer let that old man Cui Yi
我们不能再让崔毅那个老头了
Sit back and enjoy the happiness
坐下来享受幸福
A good move from the Governor
州长的好举措
Surround Wei and rescue Zhao
围魏救赵
So Cui Jiajun
So Cui Jiajun
We must give up Luoyang
必须放弃洛阳
Chijiu Yingzhou
Chijiu Yingzhou
The Zhenxi Army is left alone and unable to fight.
镇西军孤军奋战，无力作战。
Just beat them all
打败他们所有人
Send a message to Fu Yuan'er
给付媛儿留言
Zheng Guogong was greedy for power and harmed the country
郑国公贪权害国
Death is not a pity
死亡并不可惜
Tell him not to worry
告诉他不要担心
Stick to Luoyang as the top priority
坚守洛阳为第一要务
yes
是的
But where is Mrs. Wei?
可是魏夫人呢？
woman noisy
女人吵闹
I'll just ignore it
我会忽略它
Li Yi’s two brothers
李毅的两个兄弟
Are you still in Jiangnan now?
你现在还在江南吗？
Li Jun and Li Lai
Li Jun and Li Lai
None of them have the talent to lead an army
他们都没有统帅军队的才能
Still trapped in Jiangnan at this moment
此刻仍困江南
nothing to fear
没什么可怕的
Let them out
让他们出去
Dadudu means
大嘟嘟的意思
Three brothers get together
三兄弟齐聚一堂
Only then do you know who Kunpeng is
那时你才知道鲲鹏是谁
who is bird
谁是鸟
Those two birds
那两只鸟
How could you open your eyes?
你怎么能睁开眼睛？
looking at his brother
看着他的兄弟
Spread your wings and fly high
张开翅膀，展翅高飞
The Governor's clever plan
总督的巧妙计划
Since ancient times
自古以来
There will be no shortage of brothers fighting against each other
不会缺少互相争斗的兄弟
Li Yi should also try this
李毅也应该试试这个
It tastes good
味道不错
right
正确的
Come
来
Come, come, come
怎样怎样怎样
This Sun Jing used his troops strangely
这孙靖用兵奇葩
Send a large army to attack Yingzhou
派大军攻打郢州
But the main force of Cui Jiajun is here
但崔家军的主力就在这里
I'm just afraid of my father's side
我只是害怕父亲的身边
Can't last long
不能持续太久
Sun Jing is besieging Wei and rescuing Zhao.
孙景围魏救赵。
Force us to leave Luoyang
逼我们离开洛阳
I'd better leave and go back to Yingzhou.
我还是离开吧，回瀛州去吧。
It's too late to go back now
现在回去已经太晚了
What should I do?
我应该怎么办？
The main camp is far away
主营距离很远
If we could use the road to Wangzhou
如果我们可以走去望州的路
It can be on the way
它可以在路上
save a lot of time
节省很多时间
It can not only relieve the siege of Yingzhou
不仅可以解瀛州之围
We can capture Luoyang again
我们可以再次攻克洛阳
But Wangzhou is in Li Ni's hands
但望州却在李妮手里
I'm just afraid that he won't take advantage of it
我只是怕他不会利用
With our current strength
以我们现在的实力
this matter
这件事
There is still room for negotiation
仍有商量余地
What
什么
Yingzhou is in emergency
瀛州告急
The news is very reliable
这个消息非常可靠
Sun Jing's army is already on the way
孙敬大军已在路上
It seems that Cui Jiajun
看来崔家俊
There will definitely be some action
肯定会有一些动作
But they may not
但他们可能不会
Can you make it to Yingzhou?
能到瀛州吗？
If you want to get back in time
如果你想及时返回
Cui Linde needs to take the road to Wangzhou
崔林德需要走去望州的路
What do you mean
你是什​​么意思
I want to lend Wangzhou to them
我想把望洲借给他们
I'll wait for them to change
我会等他们改变
long ears
长耳朵
You accompany Miss Taozi to find medical books
你陪桃子小姐去找医书
yes
是的
The magnificence of the capital
首都的辉煌
Only visible from high altitude
仅从高空可见
Overlooking Luoyang River
俯瞰洛阳河
Hu Bing walks in confusion
胡兵迷茫地走着
Blood painted on weeds
杂草上涂满了血迹
The jackal is in full glory
豺狼正处于荣耀之中
The emperor's grandson borrowed Taibai's poem
皇孙借太白诗
Who are you mocking?
你在嘲笑谁？
I just suddenly felt emotional
我只是突然有感触
The extremely magnificent Dengdu
极其壮丽的登都
Now also involved in the war
现在也卷入了战争
There is no peace in the years
岁月里没有平静
I don’t know when I can rest
不知道什么时候才能休息
Since the emperor's grandson raised his army,
自从皇孙起兵之后，
Then you know that the war is raging
然后你就知道战争正在激烈进行
Thousands of bones
数千块骨头
Only war can end war
只有战争才能结束战争
Only then can the world be at peace
只有这样，世界才能太平
I only hope
我只希望
can be recovered as soon as possible
可以尽快恢复
This half of the river and mountains
这半边江山
Give peace to the people of the world
给世界人民带来和平
I also hope that
我也希望
You told me that day
那天你告诉我
Want to lend me Cui Jiajun
Want to lend me Cui Jiajun
People in Beijing
北京人
Help you rescue Liang Wang
帮你救出梁王
Not impossible
不是不可能
But you have to win me first
但你必须先赢得我
Listen to your tone
听你的语气
What other tricks did you come up with?
你还想出了哪些其他技巧？
Is the emperor's grandson willing?
皇孙愿意吗？
Take a gamble with me
跟我赌一把
I know the emperor is cautious
我知道皇帝很谨慎
Let me make the bet then.
那我就来打赌吧。
if i win
如果我赢了
You want me to use the road to visit the state
你想让我用这条路去参观这个州
if you win
如果你赢了
Then I am Cui Jiajun
Then I am Cui Jiajun
I will help you rescue King Liang
我来帮你救梁王
That sounds fair.
听起来很公平。
How to bet
如何投注
it's actually really easy
其实很简单
you close your eyes
你闭上眼睛
I count from one to ten
我从一数到十
before counting to ten
数到十之前
if you can't help it
如果你忍不住
opened eyes
睁开眼睛
Then you lose
那么你就输了
You won't try to take advantage of me again
你不会再试图利用我
close eyes
闭上眼睛
Sting me with a needle
用针刺我
rest assured
放心
I will never do anything
我永远不会做任何事
things that hurt you
伤害你的事情
how
如何
bet
赌注
But
但
I want to count myself
我想数一数自己
Even if you prick me with a needle
就算你用针扎我
I will never open my eyes
我永远不会睁开眼睛
Okay, then close your eyes
好吧，然后闭上眼睛
Count it yourself
自己数一下
one
一
two
二
three
三
Four
四
you lose
你输了
Can I just ignore it?
我可以忽略它吗？
Taoist priest
道士
I heard that in the Sutra Collection Pavilion of Taiqing Palace
听说太清宫藏经阁里
There is a medical book that is the only one
有一本医学书是唯一的
Can I borrow a list?
我可以借一份清单吗？
The rules set by the ancestor
祖辈定下的规矩
Books in the Sutra Pavilion
藏经阁的藏书
never loan
从不贷款
Taoist priest
道士
I am willing to sincerely
我愿意真诚地
Carrying water and sweeping for the temple
给寺庙挑水、扫地
Only the Taoist priest is invited
只邀请道士
Can you allow me to borrow from the cabinet?
你能允许我向内阁借钱吗？
Carrying water, cleaning, and cleaning are all heavy tasks.
挑水、打扫卫生、打扫卫生都是繁重的工作。
You are a girl's family
你们是一个女孩的家人
I
我
Taoist priest, I am willing to help her carry water.
道士，我愿意帮她挑水。
Taoist priest
道士
I'm also willing to help her sweep
我也愿意帮她扫地
Taoist priest, I am also willing to help.
道士，我也愿意帮忙。
Please also ask the Taoist priest for your convenience.
方便的话还请教一下道士。
Could you please go fetch some water?
你能去拿点水吗？
Please both of you
请你们俩
Go to Sasou Tibetan Scripture Pavilion
前往萨苏藏经阁
Miss Peach, let me help you.
桃子小姐，我来帮你吧。
That's not okay
那不行
You're here to help me work
你来这里是为了帮助我工作
You're not here to work for me
你不是来为我工作的
Also
还
why do you want to help me
你为什么想帮助我
I don't know either
我也不知道
Anyway, as soon as I see you
无论如何，一见到你
I just want to help you
我只是想帮助你
Look at the two of you
看看你们两个
They are all literate people
他们都是有文化的人
I would also like to ask you two to clean up
我还想请你们两个打扫卫生
Cherish books
珍惜书籍
yes
是的
You take a break
你休息一下
I'll clean it up
我会清理它
Let the emperor and grandson do the work himself
让皇孙亲自干活
This isn't appropriate, is it?
这不太合适吧？
Since I lost the bet
自从我输了赌注
Let me express my thoughts first
我先表达一下我的想法
lifelike
逼真
What a great painting
多么伟大的一幅画
This painting is named Huang Sun Lao Tu
此画名为黄孙老图
how do you feel
你感觉如何
Title is better
标题更好
This must be given to me as a gift
这必须作为礼物送给我
This is what I drew
这是我画的
Why should I give it to you?
我为什么要给你？
But what you drew is clearly me
但你画的明明是我
Nature is mine
自然是我的
why are you laughing
你笑什么
nothing
没有什么
What are you laughing at me for?
你笑我做什么？
Nothing can be said
无话可说
Say it quickly
快点说
What are you laughing at me for?
你笑我做什么？
If I had said
如果我说过
Don't be angry
别生气
Tell me first and listen
先告诉我然后听
And you, put me on your chest
而你，把我放在你的胸前
Carry it like this day and night
日日夜夜都这样带着
When I miss you
当我想念你时
You can also take it out and take a look
你也可以拿出来看看
I'm naturally happy
我自然很高兴
I smile when I'm happy
当我快乐的时候我会微笑
Glib tongue
油嘴滑舌
Thank you for your gift
谢谢你的礼物
you this person
你这个人
It's so pervasive
它如此普遍
alright
好吧
Let's get down to business
我们开始谈正事吧
Since you won the bet
既然你赢了赌注
Then I agree
那我同意
Let you use the road to visit the state
让您用路游览州
Just how can you promise me
只是你怎么能答应我
rescue my father
营救我的父亲
Then you might as well consider it
那你不妨考虑一下
Help me capture Luoyang
助我攻克洛阳
easy to say
说起来容易
Emperor Sun is so sure
孙帝如此肯定
We can capture Luoyang now
现在我们可以攻克洛阳了
First of all
首先
You and I join hands with Chen Bing under Luoyang City
你我携手陈兵洛阳城下
There is already a five-point chance of winning
已经有五分的获胜机会
Duke Zheng was captured
郑公被俘
7 points chance of winning
7分获胜机会
Although Fu Yuan'er is brave
傅媛儿虽然勇敢
But he did not know the political situation in the Ming Dynasty
但他并不了解明朝的政治局势
I don’t even know the plans of those aristocratic families.
根本不知道那些世家的打算。
9 points chance of winning
9分获胜机会
This is all already there
这一切都已经存在了
Nine points chance of winning
九分获胜机会
This Luoyang City
这个洛阳市
Isn’t it all under control?
一切不是都在掌控之中吗？
The emperor and grandson planned for the king of Liang like this
皇孙为梁王这样谋划
How lucky is the king of Liang
梁王何其幸
He is my father
他是我的父亲
Of course I will save him
我当然会救他
He is in Sun Jing's hands
他在孙静手里
I'm afraid we can capture Luoyang
恐怕能攻下洛阳
Sun Jing may not be murderous
孙靖未必有杀气
That's not as good as
那还不如
Put yourself to death and survive
把自己置于死地并生存
Fu Yuan'er took advantage of the governor's orders
傅元儿趁总督令
Absolutely not
绝对不
Save our Duke Zheng Guo
Save our Duke Zheng Guo
I'm just afraid of all the masters of the house.
我只是害怕家里所有的主人。
Fu Yuan'er won't be able to save him either.
傅媛儿也救不了他。
What should I do?
我应该怎么办？
yes
是的
We can't count on Fu Yuan'er anymore
我们不能再指望傅媛儿了
we have to rely on ourselves
我们得靠自己
Rescue the master
救出主人
That's right
这是正确的
general general
将军 将军
problem occurs
出现问题
Come in
进来
Zheng Guogong's family
Zheng Guogong's family
private army
私人军队
Knocked out the city gate guard
击倒了城门守卫
Opened the city gate
打开了城门
Lead the Western Army and Cui Jiajun
率领西军与崔家军
Entering the city
进入城市
What
什么
completion
完成
It's all over
一切都结束了
these idiots
这些白痴
I didn’t expect this Luoyang City
没想到这个洛阳市
perished in their hands
灭亡在他们手中
I'm gonna kill these idiots
我要杀了这些白痴
Died in battle
战死
Get food first
先去拿食物
Don't worry, Shichiro
别担心七郎
Zhenxi Army Cui Jiajun surrounded and attacked Luoyang
Zhenxi Army Cui Jiajun surrounded and attacked Luoyang
It is difficult to storm the city after being besieged for many days
围城多日难攻城
Li Ni used clever tactics
李妮运用巧妙的战术
Order Zheng Guogong to open the city gate privately
命令郑国公私开城门
Only then did Cui Jiajun of the Zhenxi Army sneak into Luoyang.
镇西军崔家军这才潜入洛阳。
Fu Yuan'er rose up to resist
傅媛儿奋起反抗
Leading the defenders to fight hard for two days and one night
带领守军苦战两天一夜
Finally lost
终于迷失了
I owe the governor my life
我欠州长一条命
Originally I wanted to defend Luoyang
本来我是想保卫洛阳的
Come in exchange for this life
来换取此生
did not expect
没想到
Luoyang has been lost
洛阳已失
It seems
它似乎
Today I can only take this life
今天我只能接受这一生
Gave it back to the Governor
把它还给州长
very good
非常好
Great
伟大的
The future world
未来世界
It's you who are waiting
等待的就是你
young heroes
年轻的英雄
Wait until you and him
等到你和他
When fighting for the world
当为世界而战时
How wonderful that would be
那将是多么美妙
pity
遗憾
I can't see it anymore
我再也看不见了